

Europass Curriculum Vitae

My LinkedIN profile





Personal information

Surname / First name

Address

Telephone

Personal Email

Nationality

Date of birth

Gender

Bio

Buracchi Marco

95, Via Pier Capponi, 50132, Firenze (FI), Italy

+39 3498362954

Personal: ma.buracchi@gmail.com PEC: marco.buracchi@postecert.it

science in 2015 with 110/110 cum laude.

Italian

Male

19/12/1985

I'm an ICS CyberSecurity Specialist at H-ON Consulting in Prato and I attend the Short Specialisation Programme (Master I livello) in Cybersecurity at the Pisa University. I graduated in October 2018 with 110/110 cum laude at the master's degree in computer science, "resilient and secure cyber physical systems" curricula. My master thesis was on "Side-Channel Attacks and speculative execution". Before, I obtained the bachelor degree in computer

Desired employment/ Occupational field

IT/OT/IoT security, Software Development & Research

Education and training

Dates

02/2019 - 03/2020 (expected)

Title of qualification awarded Principal subjects Short Specialisation Programme - Master I livello in cybersecurity

Applied Cryptography and Access Control, Network Security & Ethical hacking, Digital Forensics, Cyber Intelligence, Mobile and cloud security, Legal aspects of cybersecurity, Secure system configuration, device hardening and firewall management, Risk monitoring for networks and applications.

Occupational skills covered

Expert in security analysis of applications and IT systems, cyber attacks analysis, big data and machine learning applied to cybersecurity.

University of Pisa, Department of Information Engineering

CNR - Institute of Informatics and Telematics

ISCED/EQF level

Organization

7

Dates 11/2018 - 07/2019

Title of qualification awarded | CISCO Cybersecurity Scholarship Italy

Certification obtained Introduction to cybersecurity (11-2018), Cybersecurity essential (01-2019), Introduction to Cybersecurity (12-2018), Cybersecurity essential (01-2019), Introduction to Cybersecurity (12-2018)

troduction to Packet Tracer (02-2019).

Organization CISCO networking academy

Dates 01/10/2015 - 12/10/2018

Title of qualification awarded Master's degree in Resilient and Secure Cyber Physical Systems

Principal Security engineering, Security and network management, Distributed pro-

gramming for IoT, Multivariate analysis and statistical learning, Coding theory and computer security, Advanced techniques (and tools) for software development, Advanced topics in programming languages, Computer forensics, Models of sequential and concurrent systems, Quantitative analysis of systems, Real-time and critical systems, Systems modeling for verification, Advanced

numerical analysis

Organization University of Florence, Faculty of Maths, Physics and Natural Sciences

Final grade 110/110 cum laude

ISCED/EQF level 7

covered

subjects/Occupational skills

Dates 08/08/2017 - 12/08/2017

Title of qualification awarded Cornell, Maryland, Max Planck pre-doctoral research school

Principal Security and privacy, social systems, distributed systems, machine learning,

subjects/Occupational skills programming languages, and verification covered

Organization Max Planck institute for software systems, Cornell University, University of

Maryland

Dates 01/10/2012 - 09/10/2015

Title of qualification awarded Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science.

Organization University of Florence, Faculty of Maths, Physics and Natural Sciences

Final grade 110/110 cum laude

ISCED/EQF level 6

Work experiences

Dates 13/02/2020 - now

Cybersecurity consultancy applied to the OT / IACS world in accordance with the processes and requirements of the IEC 62443 standard, development of services and techniques for the analysis of customer systems in terms of infrastructure and vulnerability, risk analysis, development of specific technical reports, procedures, the choice of necessary HW and SW and the setting up of a new dedicated laboratory. Identifying and coordinating a team of technicians

dedicated to the service.

Employer H-ON consulting, Via Lepanto, 23, 59100 Prato PO

Type of business or sector | ICS CyberSecurity

Dates 01/10/2019 - now

Occupation or position held | Junior Security Engineer

Main activities Vulnerability assessment, penetration testing, research and development.

Employer

Florence Consulting Group, Via L. Lama, 23, 50019 Sesto Fiorentino Fl

Dates 28/11/2018 - 31/08/2019

Occupation or position held | Private tutor

Main activities One-on-one in-house tutoring for middle-school, high-scool and university stu-

dents.

Employer Centro didattico Matemagia - Via Baracca 166, Firenze

Type of business or sector | Private education

Dates 01/04/2015 - 01/10/2016

Occupation or position held Research helper

Main activities and responsibilities

I took part in AMADEOS project (Architecture for Multi-criticality Agile Dependable Evolutionary Open System-of-Systems) funded under the European Commission's FP7, supporting research in definition, implementation and

evaluation of mechanisms and solutions for the resilient management of the time in the smart grid and smart cities. http://amadeos-project.eu/

Employer Prof. Andrea Bondavalli, Resilient Computing Lab, Università di Firenze Type of business or sector Research and experimentation of dependable architectures and systems

Dates 01/05/2006 - 01/09/2012

center, wire EDM)

Name and address of Nuova 230AR, Arezzo, Italy (01/05/2006 - 01/05/2008)

employer | Gabry packing, Arezzo, Italy (01/05/2008 - 01/09/2012)

Type of business or sector | Manufacturing industry

Dates 01/09/2004 - 01/05/2006

Occupation or position held | Technical employee

Main activities and Direct measurement in field, fixture designer, autoCAD drawing, cutting pro-

responsibilities grams developer

Employer | Emmedi srl, Arezzo, Italy

Type of business or sector | Manufacturing industry

Personal skills and competences

Mother tongue Other language(s)

Self-assessment European level^(*)

English

Italian

Understanding			Speaking		Writing
Listening	Reading		Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
B2 Independent	C1	Proficient	B2 Independent	B2 Independent	B2 Independent
user		user	user	user	user

^(*) Common European Framework of Reference (CEF) level

Computer skills and competences

Very good computer skills, learned as self-taught and through the University. Good knowledge in the use of Kali Linux OS and various IT security and cyber intelligence tools (among the best known: Metasploit, OpenVAS, Nessus, Legion, Maltego). High expertise with many tools such as Apache NiFi, ElasticSearch, Kibana, Maven, Github, virtualization tools, Docker, test-framework.

Artistic skills and competences

I studied piano at conservatoire for 4 years. I can play guitar. I love skiing and I'm a futsal goalkeeper for more than 10 years

Driving licence(s)

category A (motorcycle owner) and category B (car owner).

Additional informations

References

Prof. Michele Boreale, University of Florence, Italy, michele.boreale(AT)unifi.it Prof. Rosario Pugliese, University of Florence, Italy, rosario.pugliese(AT)unifi.it

Personal interests

IT security, Technology, Mathematics, Physics and Science in general. Books, Music and all kind of sports. Travelling around the world.

Moune Dunki

I hereby authorize the processing of the personal data contained in this CV in compliance with the Italian Personal Data Protection Code (Legislative Decree no. 196 of 30 June 2003 and GDPR 679/16 art.13)

Signature: